JOE D. MALONE

(830) 220-0942 | Joe.D.Malone@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/joe-malone-18126673/ | github.com/JoeDonMalone

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovative full stack developer with 2+ years of demonstrated excellence in designing, building, and implementing Full Stack solutions across a variety of industries. Proven aptitude at familiarization and debugging of complex systems. Effective in a team collaboration setting and efficient in prioritizing workloads for the success of organizational objectives. Seeking a rewarding and challenging career as a Full Stack Engineer.

SKILLS

Software Development	Leadership	Soft Skills
Python	Project Management	Analytical Thinking
JavaScript	Client Focused	Detail Oriented
React	Successful Coaching	Clear Communicator
NodeJS	Strategic Planning	Collaboration
MySQL	Conflict Resolution	Problem Solving
MongoDB	Team Management	Time Management
HTML5/CSS3	Receptive	

CERTIFICATIONS

AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Secret Clearance (<u>expired</u>)

2021 2008

EXPERIENCE

Systems Integrator Control Networks Plus, Cedar Park, TX

Jul 2019 - May 2021

Collaborated with a small team of integration experts to implement supervisory controls and data acquisition (SCADA) systems in Cloud and on-premises network environments. Planning of necessary hardware/software components in complex system designs. Guiding customers in order that they make informed decisions on product purchases and network infrastructure deployments.

- Responsible for the design, build, and implementation of a full stack, single source projectestimating application which eliminated the need for multiple windows services and incorporated a relational MySQL database of historical records pertaining to all project estimates and their revisions.
- Developed tool to parse JSON objects and assign custom "tooltip" keys for corresponding screen-components, utilizing Python. Resulted in the reclamation of over 400 man-hours.
- Implementation of front-end design and controls, utilizing the Ignition framework to handle and display pertinent data in a user-friendly and concise manner.
- Reduced cellular costs for customers by interposing the MQTT("Mosquitto") messaging model for client-server data transactions.
- Utilized MySQL Database for data modeling, storage, and transaction optimization.

JOE D. MALONE

(830) 220-0942 | Joe.D.Malone@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/joe-malone-18126673/ | github.com/JoeDonMalone

Productivity Specialist/Aftermarket Sales Hexagon Metrology Inc. Irving, TX

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

Responsible for the overall increase of productivity in a customers' manufacturing process. Identified "problem areas" related to customer's shop floor and/or quality control labs. Provided software and hardware solutions, where appropriate, to hit quarterly and yearly sales figures.

- Covered Midwest-South sales territory consisting of TX, LA, AR, OK.
- Exceeded ~\$900,000.00 sales target for 2018 by 18%, despite transitioning into the role during the second half of the sales year.
- Trended towards doubling the sales target of ~\$1,250,000.00 at EOY 2019. Reached 2019 sales quota during first half of sales year, prior to company departure.

Field Service Engineer Hexagon Metrology Inc., Irving, Tx

Sep 2013 - Jul 2018

Responsible for the installation, repair, and ISO-10360 certifications of Bridge and Gantry-style Coordinate Measuring Machines (CMM). Focused on delivering outstanding services on behalf of the customer's pursuit of manufacturing and quality excellence.

- Covered Midwest-South service territory consisting of TX, LA, AR, OK, IL
- 491 customer certifications
- 61 successful repairs, 0 failed repairs
- Trained 3 new hires for team of 7
- Mentored over a period of 2.5 years by world Senior Service Engineer, working closely with him to provide priority customer solutions.
- Primary Service Engineer for multiple customers, including Raytheon Co. (Lemmon Ave.), GE Oil & Gas, and Bray Controls

Avionics Technician U.S. Navy, Norfolk Naval Station, VA

Sep 2008 – Sep 2013

Responsible for the safe flight operations of eight MH-60S helicopters. Retained/utilized multiple cross-division "Collateral Duty Inspector" qualifications necessary to enforce and ensure a structured and by-the-book approach to all aircraft maintenance.

- Maintained and updated Cryptology syncs for squadron secret radio communications and IFF transactions
- Managed up to 30 team members in their shift maintenance activities.
- 100% mission sortie rating over the duration of 15,000 hours of Operation Enduring Freedom
- Created and administered Command Training Program for over 320 team members

EDUCATION

The Coding Boot Camp at University of Texas at Austin

June 2021

Full Stack Developer Certificate

Marble Falls High School May 2007

Diploma